Trice, Harrison, Papers /4313
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Harrison Trice Papers
1959-1996
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Trice, Harrison
Sonnenstuhl, William
/4313
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
Reprints of articles by Professor Trice.
8507399
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, June 26, 2014
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 04, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Harrison Miller Trice was Professor Emeritus in the Department of Organizational Behavior at the School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Cornell University, where he had been a member of the faculty since 1955. Professor Trice's major contribution to his discipline has been the integration of the study of alcohol and drugs with the study of the workplace. More than any other social scientist, he was responsible for integrating occupational and organizational sociology with the study of alcohol and drugs.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4312: William Sonnenstuhl Papers
Trice, Harrison Miller, 1920-; Sonnenstuhl, William J., 1946-
8507399
- Trice papers (Box 1)
  - Trice (1969) The Role of Ceremonials in Organizational Behavior (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Trice (1977) A Sociological Property of Drugs (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Beyer, Janice (1981) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Trice (1965) Belasco Identifying and comforting the Alcoholism Employee (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Trice (1957) A Study of the Process of Affiliation w/ Alcoholics Anonymous (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Trice (1977) A Summary of Recent Studies Done by the Program on Alcoholism and Occupational Health (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Truce (1968) Belasco Supervisory Training about Alcoholics and Other Problem Employees (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Trice (1977) Testimony Before Subcommittee on Alcoholism and Drug Abuse, Senate Committee on Human Resources (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Belasco 1968 Trice Training as A Change Agent: A 4-way Evaluation Design (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Trice (1973) Differential Social Support Among U.S. University Students for the Use of Various Drugs (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Trice (1977) Inside and Outside Change Agents in Occupational Programming (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Trice (1961) Industry Will Assist the Judge (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - French Magee (1973) Incidence of the Emotionally Disturbed w/in the Administrative Units of Large Organization (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Trice Ritzer Individual and Occupational Levels of Professionalism (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Hunt Trice Beyer (1976) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Ritzer Belasco Trice (1968) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Trice the Role concerns, and needs of Supervisors in Occupational alcoholism Programs (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Belasco Trice Ritzer (1969) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Trice (August 1981) Evaluating the Effectiveness of Interventions Designed to Reduce or Control Problem Drinking (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Trice (1972) The Troubled Employee (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Belasco Trice (July 1969) Unanticipated Returns of Training (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Trice Penfield (1961-summer) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Trice (1964) The Weighted Application Blank - A Caution (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Trice (1959) "What we know About Alcoholism in Industry (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - (1976) Women, Alcohol, and Drugs (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Trice (1957) (Vol 3, #2) Work Accidents and the Problem Drinker - A Case Study - (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Trice (1965) Belasco Workmen's Compensation and the Emotionally Disturbed Employee (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Roman 1969 Trice Self Reaction: A Neglected Dimension of "Labeling Theory" (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Trice Roman Belasco (1969) Selection for Treatment (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Beyer Trice Stevens (1976) The Routinization of Change: Implementation of Policy in Federal Organizations (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Beyer Trice (1977) Organizational Structure and the Implementation pf Change w/in Federal Sector Organizations (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Trice (1956) The "Outsiders" Role in Field Study (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Trice (1977) Clinical and Nonclinical Programs in the Workplace: Some Overseas Applications (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Roman Trice (1969) Change and Mental Health (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Trice (1973) A Discussion of the Broad Brush and Employee Alcoholism Programs (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Roman (1985) Blum The Seven Core Dimensions of EAP Practice (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Belasco Trice (1969) The Assessment of Change in Training and Therapy (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Stevens Beyer Trice (1978 (vol. 21) Assessing Personal role and Organizational Predictor's Managerial Commitment (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Trice (1970) Alcoholism and the Work World (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Trice Roman (1973) (Chap. 16) - Alcoholism and the Worker (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Trice Roman (1971) Alcoholism and the Employee (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Trice (1956) Alcoholism: Group Factors in Etiology and Therapy (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Trice Belasco (1959) The Alcoholic and his Supervisor (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Trice Belasco (1966) The Alcoholic and the Steward: A Union Problem (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Trice (1958) Alcoholics Anonymous (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Trice Belasco (1970) The Aging Collegian Drinking Pathologies Among (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Trice (1959) The Affiliation Motive and Readiness to Join A.A. (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Trice (1958) Absenteeism Among High -Status and Low-Status Problem drinkers (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Roman (1968) Trice Occupational Role Change and Mental Health (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Trice (1964) Nigh Watchmen: A Study of the Isolated Occupation (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Trice (1957) New Light on Identifying the Alcoholic employee (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Beyer (1982) Trice A Neglected Aspect of the Managerial Role: Predicting (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Roman Trice (1967) A Multiple Factor Approach to Schizophrenia and Social Class (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Trice (1959) A Methodology for Evaluating Conference Leadership Training: Preliminary Findings (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Roman Trice (1970) Mental Health in Work Organizations: A Re-Examinations (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Beyer Trice (1980) Managerial Ideologies and the Use of Discipline (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Stevens Beyer Trice (1976) Managerial Commitment: A Multivariate and Path Analytic Approach. (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Trice (1961) Job Placement of the Alcoholic Employee (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Trice Beyer (1981) Job-Based Alcoholism Programs: Underlying Concepts and Strategy (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - (1962) The Job Behavior of Problem Drinkers (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Roman Blum; The Core Technology of Employee, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Trice (1984) An Uncoordinated Intervention (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Trice (1981) Further Musings from a Cockeyed Optimist (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Trice (1970) Roman Socio psychological Predictors of Affiliation w/ A.A. (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Trice (1957) Sociological Factors in Association w/ A.A. (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Trice Pittman (1958) Social Organization and Alcoholism: A Review of Significant Research Since 1940 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Roman (1968) Trice The Sick Rule, Labelling Theory, and the Deviant Drinker (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Trice (1965) (Vol. 7, no. 5) Reaction of Supervisors to Emotionally Disturbed Employees (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Trice Wahl (1958) (Vol 19, no. 4) A Rank Order Analysis of the Symptoms of Alcoholism (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Roman (1972) Trice Psychiatric Impairment Among "Middle Americans" Survey of Work Organizations (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Trice (1959) The Problem Drinker on The Job (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Trice (1956) (vol 2, #3) The Problem Drinker in Industry (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Trice (1961) Present Day Approaches to Alcohol and Alcoholism (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Beyer Stevens Trice (1980) Predicting How Federal Managers Perceive Criteria Used for Their Promotion (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Trice Ritzer (1972) The Personnel Manager and his Self-image (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Trice (1960) Personnel Appraised and Job Description in Extension Supervision (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Hunt Trice (1977) he Occupational Programming (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Ritzer Trice (1970) (Vol. 48) Trice on the Problems of Clarifying Commitment Theory (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Trice Roman (1972) Soft Drugs, the Campus and You (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Lecture (1974) Some notes on Evaluating Existing Programs (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Trice (1976) Panel Discussion Paper - ADPA Annual Meeting - (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Roman Trice (1974) (Chpt.6) Strategies of Preventive Psychiatric and Social Reality: The Case of Alcoholism (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Report (winter 1975, Vol. 11, no 2) Stress on the Job (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - A Study of the Occupational Self-Image of Personnel Managers (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Trice Beyer Hunt (1976) Formal Testimony Before Manpower and Housing Subcommittee of the Committee on (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Trice Beyer; Federal Unions: Interorganizational Pressures toward Conformity with Personnel Policies (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Trice Beyer (1984) Work Related Outcomes of the constructive - Confrontation strategy in a job-based Alcoholism program (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Coppess Beiseigel Trice (1977) Report of the Cornell Evaluation of the Corporate Headquarters Alcoholism Project (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Trice Roman (1973) Evaluation of Training: Strategy Tactics And Problems (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Trice (1981) Evaluating the Effectiveness of Interventions (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Jaskolka Beyer Trice (1985) Measuring and Predicting Managerial Success (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Stevens Beyer Trice (1980) Managerial Receptivity and Implementation of Policies (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Trice 1981 An Evaluation of Program Evaluations (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Trice (1977) (Vol. 7) Evaluation of Consultants and Coordinators (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Trice (1968) Evaluation of Alcoholics Anonymous (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Trice Beyer Hunt (1978) Evaluating Implementation of a Job-based Alcoholism Policy (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Trice 1981 Encouraging Abstinence among Students: A Natural Approach to Primary Prevention of Alcoholism (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Trice (1962) (Vol. 14) The Employed Alcoholic (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Ritzer (1969) (vol. 47) (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Trice Belasco (1966) Emotional Health and Employer Responsibility (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Stafford Knick Rehm Trice (1966) Employee Attitudes Toward Performance Appraisal (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - Trice Wasmuth (July 1962) Effective Hiring in Small Business Organizations (Box 1, Folder 102)
  - Trice 1976 Drugs, Drug Abuse, and the Week Place (Box 1, Folder 103)
  - Trice Roman (1974) (Chapter 7) Dilemmas of Evaluation in Community Mental Health Organizations (Box 1, Folder 104)
  - Trice Beyer (1977) Three/Differential use of an Alcoholism Policy in federal Organizations by Skill Level of Employees (Box 1, Folder 105)
  - Trice Lodahl Bailey (1973) Differential Social Support Among U.S. University Students for the use of various drugs (Box 1, Folder 106)
  - Roman Trice (1970) The Development of Deviant Drinking Behavior- Occupational Risk Factors (Box 1, Folder 107)
  - Trice Roman (1970) Delabeling, Relabeling, and Alcoholics Anonymous (Box 1, Folder 108)
  - Trice Roman (1971) Constructive Confrontation (Box 1, Folder 109)
  - Roman Trice Comparative Characteristics of Schizophrenics with Labels of Differing Intensity (Box 1, Folder 110)
  - Applied Research Job - Based Alcoholism + EAP's, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 111)
  - AA + EAP: The Historical Link, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 112)
  - New Light on identifying the Alcoholic employee, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 113)
  - The Core Technology of Employer Assistance Programs, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 114)
  - Alcoholic Employee, 1961-1965 (Box 1, Folder 115)
  - Clinical + Nonclinical Programs in the Workplace (Box 1, Folder 116)
  - Alcoholism + the Work World, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 117)
  - The Impact of Federal Sector Unions on Supervisors Use of Personnel Policies, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 118)
  - A Study of the Process of Affiliation with Alcoholics Anonymous, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 119)
  - Sociological Factors in Association with A.A., 1957 (Box 1, Folder 120)
  - The Affiliation, Motive, and Readiness to Join A.A., 1959 (Box 1, Folder 121)
  - Managerial Ideologies and the Use of Discipline, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 122)
  - Social Control in Work settings, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 123)
  - Social Controls in the Workplace, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 124)
  - The Sick Role, Labelling Theory, and the Deviant Drinker, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 125)
  - Evaluation of Consultants and Coordinators, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 126)
  - A Sociological Property of Drugs, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 127)
  - The Best-Worst Technique for Measuring Work Performance, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 128)
  - Supervisory Training about Alcoholics and Other Problem Employees (Box 1, Folder 129)
  - The Problem Drinker on the Job, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 130)
  - EAP - Where Do We Stand in 1983? (Box 1, Folder 131)
  - The Personnel Manager and His Self-Image, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 132)
  - Deviance and Work, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 133)
  - Truth + Fiction in Occupational Stories: Case of Troubled Supervisor, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 134)